Mss.Rec.139 Mss.Rec.139
American Philosophical Society
Indian language recordings
1959, circa 1960-1961, 1963
Mss.Rec.139
American Philosophical Society
4.0 Tape(s)
Seneca dance songs recorded at Coldspring, New York. Also includes a story, personal narratives, and interview discussions about sickness, medicine, witchcraft, and related Seneca ceremonies and customs.
4 sound tape reels (4 hr., 16 min.)
Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
Reel 4
Related Archival Materials
George S. Snyderman Papers (Ms.Coll.51).
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Accessioned with and removed from the George S. Snyderman Papers (Ms.Coll.51).
Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Social life and customs; Sound recordings
- Audio recordings
  - Round Dances, 6 songs, 1963-06-27; 01-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:11:40; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Snyderman, Michael
    Scope and Contents note
    Duplicate of original recording on reel 2 from same collection.
    Existence and Location of Originals note
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Sound tape reel) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music
  - Shake the Bush, 8 songs, 1963-06-27; 01-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:47; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Snyderman, Michael
  - Rabbit Songs, 5 songs, 1963-06-27; 01-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:35; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Snyderman, Michael
  - Crocodile, 1959-09-18; 01-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:24; Cusick, Chief; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
  - Raccoon, 1959-09-18; 01-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:34; Cusick, Chief; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
  - Ladies' Dance, 10 songs, circa 1960; 01-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:12:29; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Sprague, Lorne; Sprague, Raymond
    Grand River (Ont.); Seneca dance; Seneca Indians--Music
  - Old Moccasins, 10 songs, circa 1960; 01-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:52; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Sprague, Lorne; Sprague, Raymond
  - Round Dances, 6 songs, circa 1960; 01-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:32; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Sprague, Lorne; Sprague, Raymond
  - Grab Your Partner, 6 songs, circa 1960; 01-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:38; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Sprague, Lorne; Sprague, Raymond
  - Feather Dance, circa 1960; 01-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:04; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Sprague, Lorne; Sprague, Raymond
  - Fish Dance, circa 1960; 01-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:27; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Sprague, Lorne; Sprague, Raymond
  - Women's Dance, circa 1960; 01-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:38; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Sprague, Lorne; Sprague, Raymond
  - Feather Dance, circa 1960; 01-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:39; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Sprague, Lorne; Sprague, Raymond
  - Kee Way, circa 1961; 01-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:41; Dowdy, Herb; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
  - Round Dances, 6 songs, 1963-06-27; 02-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:02; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Snyderman, Michael
  - Shake the Bush, 8 songs, 1963-06-27; 02-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:02; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Snyderman, Michael
  - Rabbit Songs, 5 songs, 1963-06-27; 02-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:49; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Snyderman, Michael
  - Discussion of Avery Jimerson's Seneca name, 1963-06-27; 02-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:25; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Names, Seneca
  - Kee Way [1 of 2], circa 1961; 02-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:30:30; Dowdy, Herb; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
  - Kee Way [2 of 2], circa 1961; 02-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:25:47; Dowdy, Herb; Jimerson, Walter; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
  - Story of how a young man became a medicine man, 1963-06-20; 03-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:32; Redeye, Clara; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
    In English only.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Medicine
  - Story of how a young man became a medicine man, 1963-06-20; 03-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:38; Redeye, Clara; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
    In Seneca only.
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Medicine; Seneca language
  - Story and discussion of two times Sherman Redeye got sick, 1963-06-20; 03-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:23; Redeye, Clara; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca Indians--Medicine; Seneca Indians--Social life and customs
  - Story about a dream Clara had when Sherman first got sick, 1963-06-20; 03-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:22; Redeye, Clara; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca Indians--Folklore
  - Discussion of early morning curing ceremony, little people, and Dark Dance, 1963-06-20; 03-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:59; Redeye, Clara; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Medicine; Seneca Indians--Social life and customs
  - Discussion of witches and little water medicine, 1963-06-20; 03-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:06:28; Redeye, Clara; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
    Allegany Indian Reservation (N.Y.); Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Medicine; Witchcraft
  - Discussion of killing a chicken to ward off bad medicine, 1963-06-20; 03-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:49; Redeye, Clara; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-
  - Round Dances, 6 songs, 1963-06-27; 04-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:13:43; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Snyderman, Michael
    Duplicate of original recording on reel 2 from same collection. Runs slightly slow with uncorrected background hum.
  - Shake the Bush, 8 songs, 1963-06-27; 04-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:11; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Snyderman, Michael
  - Rabbit Songs, 5 songs, 1963-06-27; 04-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:07:00; Jimerson, Avery; Snyderman, George Simon, 1908-; Snyderman, Michael